<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ClassificationScheme uri="urn:ebu:metadata-cs:ContractTypeCodeCS_2008">
	<!-- ##################################################################### 
	     CONTRACT TYPE CODE                                                    
	     Definition: A list of typical types of contracts in broadcasting
	     
	     The following Creative Commons Rights apply to the use of this EBU resource:
	     http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/
	     
	     Owner: EBU Technical Department
	     Author: Jean-Pierre Evain
	     Contact: evain@ebu.ch
	     
	     ##################################################################### -->
   
   <Alias>EBUContractTypeCode</Alias>
   
   <Term  termID="1">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Commitment to Produce</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract in which one party promises to produce a specified item for another. The contract may specify the timescales and costs involved as well as the nature of the final product. Typically, contracts to produce programmes for television and radio include clauses concerning the time before transmission the programme must be ready by, and the storage format which must be used for the delivery</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>
   
   <Term  termID="2">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Employment Contract</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract where one party (typically but not always a person) undertakes to provide labour for another party (typically but not always an organisation) in return for remuneration. Employment contracts may be open ended, for a fixed term (e.g. three months), or for a specific task</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>
   
   <Term  termID="3">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Licence to Publish</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract giving the right to publish the material concerned in a specified format in a specified territory. This may apply to publication in the form of physical copies of items such as books, Cds, DVDs or videos, or publication as a broadcasting event such as a television or radio programme, or the right to publish material on a web site</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>
   
   <Term  termID="4">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Licence to Use</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract giving the right to use the material concerned in a specified format in a specified territory. Examples of this may be the insertion of clips, images or pieces of music into other productions</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>
   
   <Term  termID="5">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Transfer of Ownership by Donation</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract transferring ownership of something from one party to another without any transfer of money or goods in return. A donation may be of physical property, money or intellectual property rights</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>
   
   <Term  termID="6">
      <Name xml:lang="en">Transfer of Ownership by Sale</Name>
      <Definition xml:lang="en">A contract transferring ownership of something from one party to another in return for a payment. This may refer to the sale of actual physical property, or of intellectual property such as rights. The payment will usually be in money using a specified currency, but can be made in kind using other property or a combination of goods and money</Definition>
      <Reference/>
      <ChangeComment>First version after conversion of P/META into XML</ChangeComment>
      <ChangeVersionDate/>
      <ValidityFlag>1</ValidityFlag>
      <DeprecatedVersionDate/>
   </Term>

</ClassificationScheme>